

3 Cranleigh House, Cranleigh Street, London NW1 1NT ecem.ergin.17@ucl.ac.uk / www.ecemergin.com +44.759.7437058 (Cell)

Professional Summary

Has been working at the intersection of HCI, digital media and architecture. Skilled in designing experiments; comfortable with combining qualitative and quantitative methods to provide triangulated data. Run workshops with a focus on VR and 360 footages including 3D scanning. As well, participated in public engagement projects in the UK and overseas locations.

Education

The Bartlett School of Architecture, University College London, London, UK

PhD in $Architectural\ Space\ and\ Computation$ _ Present _ Supervisor: Ava Fatah Modules included:

° History of Digital Architecture (audit) w/ Mario Carpo

Yale University School of Architecture, New Haven, CT, USA

 $\it Visiting\ Scholar _$ Spring 2020 _ Supervisor: Keller Easterling Modules included:

- ° Architecture and Abstraction w/ Pier Vittorio Aureli
- ° Renaissance & Modern II w/ Peter Eisenmann, Kurt Forster
- ° Exhibitionism: Politics of Display w/ Joel Sanders
- ° Globalisation Space (audit) w/ Keller Easterling

Pratt Institute, Brooklyn, New York, USA

MS: Architecture, Post-Professional _ May 2016

- Modules included:
 - ° A Thousand Years of Nonlinear History w/ Manuel De Landa
 - ° A Science of the environment w/ Sanford Kwinter
 - ° Material Articulation w/ Ferda Kolatan
 - Design Studio w/ David Ruy

Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul, Turkey

Master of Science in Architectural Design _ May 2014

Politecnico di Milano, Milano, Italy

Erasmus program _ September 2009-August 2010

Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul, Turkey

Bachelor of Architecture _ August 2012

Publications

Framed, Therefore Real in London Design Festival 2020

Framed, Therefore Real in Materia Arquitectura edited by Stephannie Fell [In Press]

Bartlett SoA Instagram Take over - July 2020

<u>Cultural Bulletin</u> – Summer Issue 2019 / Photographs / Pages 42-45

Ecem Ergin Page 1 | 3

Flowing Bodies: Exploring the Micro and Macro Scales of Bodily Interactions with Urban Media Installations – June 2019, Conference Paper

Pervasive Displays Research: What's Next? - Journal Paper

<u>Times Square in the Era of Post-Truth Politics</u> – November 2018, Conference Paper

<u>UCL Doctoral School Handbook</u> 2018/19 The Art of Research / Collage

Bartlett Doctoral Review 2018 / Paper and Photograph

<u>Welcoming the Orange Collars: Robotic Performances in Everyday City Life</u> – June 2018, Conference Paper

Professional Experience

MA: Historic Urban Environments, The Bartlett School of Architecture, London, UK

Post Graduate Teaching Assistant, September 2019- Present

-Assisting teaching staff as well as students of the master program

Modules included:

- ° Design Practice for Historic Environments
- Surveying and Recording of Cities
- Issues in Historic Urban Environment

International Night-time Design Initiative, New York, US/ London, UK

Researcher, June 2019- Present

-Curating and creating content, as well as reconsidering the branding.

Purpose Group, London, UK

Photographer, August 2018 – July 2019

-Responsible for documentation of workspaces.

Purpose Group, London, UK

Project Manager, August 2018 – July 2019

-Duties included outsourcing necessary drawing jobs, editing graphics, and preparing images for promotional materials.

Rhizome Architects, Istanbul, Turkey

Architect, September 2016 - September 2017

-Participated in design decision and presentation materials.

PRATT 3D LABS, New York, USA

Printing Assistant, February 2016- May 2016

-Printing 3D models with various 3D printers.

ITU Erasmus Office, Istanbul, Turkey

Erasmus Student Coordinator, August 2013- May 2014

-Organised documents and assisted exchange students with their inquiries.

Lotus Group, Istanbul

Architect, June 2013- April 2014

-Designed two architectural projects as follows:

Hacettepe University, Beytepe Campus master plan, Ankara/Turkey

- -Accomplished site plans and renderings in different scales
- -Researched governmental regulations for sustainable energy resources
- -Developed design strategies to raise efficiency

Ecem Ergin Page 2 | 3

Pamukkale University, Dormitory, Denizli/Turkey

- -Investigated different layouts for maximum privacy in dormitories
- -Improved living conditions for individuals
- -Evaluated plan schemas, elevations, sections, details and renderings

Scholarships and Grants

- UCL-Yale Exchange Fund- Spring 2020 (Tuition Fee)
- Bartlett Architecture Research fund, February 2020 and October 2019
- Bartlett Conference Fund, November 2018 and June 2018
- MS: Architecture Merit-based Scholarship, Pratt Institute, 2015-2016
- Ministry of Education in Turkey, Higher Education in Foreign Countries Scholarship (Second place country-wide from all submissions)

Exhibitions & Workshops

Research Images Exhibition w/ the work titled "As if Hegel was one of us" UCL, London, April 2019

BREAK//LINE Residency Workshop, The Bartlett, London, February 2018

WHIST Interactive theatre and VR Workshop with Esteban Fourmi and Aoi Nakamura The Bartlett, November 2017

Thinking in Sound, Sam Auinger Workshop with Sanford Kwinter, Pratt Institute, NY, September 2015

European Symposium on Research In Architecture And Urban Design November 2014

7th International Deleuze Conference/ Models, Machines and Memories, Istanbul, July 2014, Organization Committee

Anavatos: The Invisible City, Anavatos Workshop with University of Bari, Chios, Greece, September 2014

Raise your head, Datascope Workshop with TU Delft, Istanbul, May 2013

In between layers, City Walls Workshop with Aristoteles University, Thessaloniki, July 2012

24 Hour workshop beyond the city Beijing/Istanbul/Turin/Delft/Pennsylvania, Istanbul, October 2012

Certifications

- Student Representative for Architectural Space and Computation PhD program/ Nov 2019- Present
- UCL Arena One training for PGTAs / September 2019

Interests

- Photographing the built environment over 15 years, exhibited several times in Istanbul. Selection of works could be found: www.instagram.com/art_ik_er
- Video editing enthusiast with a focus on video art.
- Have been drawing caricatures, mostly related to architectural issues. Working on a child book with these drawings.
- Motorcycle and bike user participated local tours in Istanbul and elsewhere.
- Co-founder of a creative club at Istanbul Technical University called "Cik-Art".
- Secured 1st or 2nd place in ten chess tournaments as an individual or a team member.
- Was head of the debate team in high school, won local awards.

Ecem Ergin Page 3 | 3